to test the mic good evening everyone and i'll call to order this meeting of lancaster city
council for tuesday november 11th 2025 welcome a couple reminders at the top of the meeting first if you haven't done so already please go ahead and silence your phones and devices also a reminder that this meeting and its participants are being recorded
at the during our meeting this evening there will be opportunities for public comment the
The first general public comment period is for residents that registered in advance
to speak about items that are not on the agenda. Residents may also comment on individual items on our legislative agenda. That's section 9 tonight.
Finally, a second public comment period will be at the end of our agenda for any other speakers wishing to address council about items not previously covered. All speakers will be reminded to begin
with their name and block of residence for our meeting record and address their comments toward council.
For all speakers, please be advised that public comment is not a question and answer period. Comments are limited to three minutes per speaker. And to keep time, I'll be using the timer light. It will turn green when three minutes begins. It will blink yellow, hopefully, when there's one minute remaining and then blink red at the end of three minutes. And I appreciate everyone's cooperation in advance to maintain order and equal time. Lastly, speakers addressing council, members of the audience, and members of council will be expected to conduct themselves an orderly manner and remain respectful of others and now for all of those who
are willing and able please rise for the Pledge of Allegiance mr. Harris would
you please call the roll of members yes madam president mr. men here mr. Roya
here mr. Cleese miss Craig here misty is here mr. Hirsch here the president Baker here councillor clicks is excused this evening our next item is the approval of the minutes of the October 2020 excuse me October 28th 2025 meeting of council motion to approve second we have a motion and a second on the
minutes councillors any comments on them hearing none mr. Harris mr. men I mr. Arroyo I miss Craig all right misty is I mr. Hirsch all right president Baker I I still move to proclamations honors and resolutions of recognition we do have one of those this evening we have resolution number 78 2025 mr. Harris if you would a resolution of the council the city of Lancaster honoring Porfirio Paul
Irizarry jr. for his service in the United States Navy motion to approve second Thank You counselors we have a motion and a second this is being introduced by councillor Diaz councillor Diaz Thank You president today we pause with pride to honor encourage the courageous men and women who have served
and continue to serve our nation we offer our deepest gratitude to all veterans within our workforce throughout our community for their sacrifice and
dedication of service as of 2025 there are approximately sixteen point two
million living in the United States that are part of the military veteran
residents in the U.S., 50 states of Washington and Puerto Rico. As of 2025, Lancaster City has approximately 1,577,000 military veterans, according to the U.S. Census. Among those living in Lancaster is in Lancaster City is E-5 Boatswine Mate. That's Petty Officer Paul Idesari that served in the Navy during Vietnam War. The true honor for me is to present this
resolution to a Puerto Rican American born citizen who sacrificed his life during the Vietnam War.
It is fitting and proper for our city to honor all veterans and forever honor and remember the sacrifice and dedications and serve our nation along with all the veterans across the country and Puerto Rico.
Thank you very much, Councilor Diaz. Is Mr. Irizarry here this evening? Yes. Thank you.
i would love before we have any additional council comments um if we might get to hear from him if
possible paul do you want to make a comment you can come right up on to the microphone here and it might just need to be switched on at the top if you want to just double check and make sure
that it's turned on before you speak yeah okay perfect welcome good evening good evening uh
first and foremost i want to congratulate mr arroyo as our next mayor of lancaster city and i'm proud that we finally got a puerto rican mayor in lancaster city i lived here all my life but i grew up here in lancaster i joined the military at the age of 17 years old i've been through the vietnam war i've been through the lebanese war and i have seen many of our comrades either being killed or wounded today i want to give a thanks to those men and women that dedicated their life to serve this country and not just to serve this country but i was raised in puerto rico till i was eight years old so i also want to dedicate this to my puerto ricans in puerto rico because they also have sacrificed so much for this country besides that we have a lot of puerto ricans here in lancaster that are military personnel uh i would like to see that you contribute to that not just today i'm probably the first one here that is being recognized but there's so many of us that should be recognized but in the city of Lancaster we have so many homeless veterans here in Lancaster and I read an article that the Lancaster County Prison they were asking for requests on what to do with that we have a lot of homeless veterans here we can build that facility and help some of these veterans that are here in lancaster and get them out from where they're at they are homeless but yet they're wounded not in their mind but they have been wounded and they and and they're and they shown i see them out in the street i talk to them and i feel for them because there was a time that i was there but i built myself up and I came out. I have a good friend of mine that I know. You know, most veterans come home, but there's other veterans that don't. And those that come home feel the pain and are forgotten for what they have done to this country. We need to look at these veterans and appreciate the sacrifice they have given to have everybody in here, and not just here, but across the United States, free. We have so many that are in need of help, and a lot of the government don't see us. I was one of them. I'm a little nervous, so, you know, I'm in. No worries at all. Well, I don't think we had told you you needed to make a speech, so I appreciate it. I also want to acknowledge one thing. How many of you in here are veterans? You know the sacrifices that you have made for this country. These individuals who are here that are in the military. And our city clerk, Mr. Harris, as well. Terry Ullinger. I just met the other one, too. And thank you for your service. Thank you for your service. I will do it all over again if I was called back to duty I would do it all over again today we are in deep times troubled times we have a war in Israel with Gaza we have a war with Ukraine and and Russia we have China on one side that could be troubling because they want Taiwan and what I see today and the division that we have in this country we are in a verge of war not just you know it saddened me that we have to be divided so much in this country whether we're Republicans or Democrats that we don't realize that we're here in this country together we may have differences in this world but we're here together and when we are called to duty we will serve you know there's a there's a real good speech back in 19 in the 1960s with john f kennedy who said one thing and i still remember that but i will add a little bit more to it he stated and he said on his speech ask don't ask what your country can do for you but ask what you can do for your country. I did, many of us veterans did. It's time for them to give back to us as military personnel. We sacrificed, we died, a lot of us died so that this country can be free. With that, I thank all my veterans. I thank Terry, good friend. Johnny, thank you. I haven't forgot you, I know you're the mayor now. and thank you for your service and for yours thank you thank you for your
service Mr. Irizarry and for your words this evening I'm really glad that we're getting a chance to honor just one of our many veterans in our community on
this Veterans Day we have a vote to make but I first will open it up for any additional council comments on the resolution councillor Hirsch thank you Thank you.
Counselor Diaz for introducing this important day.
Thank you Mr. Irizarry and all the other veterans that have served
were forever indebted to to you for your service. Thank you. DIRECTOR HARRIS BUSHCHEY KAYEYEN:" Thank you. Any additional counsel comments on the resolution. DIRECTOR HARRIS BUSHCHEY KAYEYEN:" Real quick. DIRECTOR HARRIS BUSHCHEY KAYEYEN:" Counselor Diaz. DIRECTOR DIAZ.: I would love to have my dad here.
I called him up and said hey dad thank you for your service.
And he just laughed at me he goes well that was many many years ago he is 82 now and he was stationed in France but he always makes me remember to be tough not to take any BS from anybody that's what my dad taught me because I think he really wanted me to go into the military even though I was too skinny back then they didn't accept 98 pounds but I'm always happy to know that my grandfather her for World War II my father and some of my
cousins that were even in the Iraq war and were injured that they're keeping us as a free country and protecting the borders and protecting us all over the world thank you again senority Saturday and all those veterans that are here today you any additional council comments on the resolution for me council president council royal just wanted to say Thank You mr. Zari for your service and to all the veterans that are here this evening as well thank you for your service on this Veterans Day and with that I'll open it up to any comments from the public on the resolution hearing none mr. Harris if
you call the roll mr. Mudd aye mr. Roya aye miss Craig all right miss Diaz mr. Hirsch all right I'm President Baker aye thank you and
congratulations again councillor Diaz do you have a presentation copy to give
great a nicer background over there oh hi thank you congratulations again that
will take us to our first public comment period for this meeting again as a reminder this period is reserved for residents who contacted the city clerk
ahead of time to request the opportunity to address council again comments
durations are limited to three minutes per speaker I'll keep time with the
light here and please begin with your name and block of residence for a
meeting record mr. Harris do we have speakers for this period we do madam president first is Melissa Hernandez good evening you can move that down as far as you need it yep perfect thank you definitely hi good evening I too am a
veteran huh believe it or not I'm short but I made it thank you miss Hernandez before you begin if I could just remind you to address your comments to word council and begin with your name and block of residence okay time is yours
Melissa Hernandez I am a business owner and he body to restaurant or 602 South
Lyme and also a body mix mini-mart 635 South Lyme and I'm here today with
Israel. He invited me, uh, to talk about, um, our city and, um, and my business and how, uh, the economy is, is, is, uh, and the, um, the snap, um, stoppage, I should say, uh, has affected my business. Um, people don't have the funds to spend as much as they used to. and so I'm keeping afloat and not and not just because of the EBT I'm just saying because of the community in a whole everything's just so expensive these days and anyways I represent Lancaster City I'm I'm a veteran and I grew up on South Plum Street in Lancaster and so it feels good to have my businesses right where I grew up yeah and so I don't know if you remember Teen Haven. Teen Haven is where I used to go when I was younger for Bible school and now I have a I have a mini mart there so it feels good and so I plan on staying there and just know that you know what we do what we can in this economy and you know I'm a veteran I'm tough and so
here I am so any question for me we don't typically take questions from the
audience on public comment but I do appreciate you coming and and talk about
that I think it's important yeah the how the SNAP benefits don't just impact the
folks that receive them but also the businesses where those people spend those dollars so thank you very much all right thank you Mr. Harris any
additional speakers for this period yes madam president next is Israel Gonzalez
good evening you can move that wherever you need it you can move that right on back up that's just fine my name is Israel Gonzalez and I'm from the 300 block of South Ann Street and I wanted to also uphold Melissa Rodriguez Hernandez for their time their service thank you yeah so excited to get the community involved I've been in contact with Public Works about the situation that's happening in our alleyway we have my father speaking later we are concerned about commercial development and activity happening in a residential area not only perhaps large commercial vehicles but also the possibility of non-residents doing either business or storage units it's very excited and synchronous the synchronicity between the bill 14 that's going to be proposed how it feels so align with an issue we've heard so again rehabilitating democracy and people power the voice so I think that just leads beautifully into snap what instability that was able to happen from a decision there seems to be some sand
on our foundation so if we could organize I know there's so much potential with mayors being elected around the tri-state area some kind of
organizing bottom up so we don't just feel this top-down pressure on instability to use people power and present some kind of motion or activity that we have stability there's potential in the next local government to do something exciting and new be remember a legacy of sorts our our local economy has this beautiful dance of immigration. In the last 60 years, how we've grown, the Latino and
black community has grown so much. In the 60s, I think there was almost no one. In the 90s, it blew
up to 10,000 folks. And even now, there's like 43% of us are non-white. But along with that comes this intense poverty. And along with that comes this access to SNAP. But even if you're below or above the poverty line, folks are still on SNAP. And then there's the economy.
About 5% of Lancaster County's economy is on SNAP.
I think Lancaster runs on a almost $200 million budget. And SNAP, we receive about, I think, 10 million out of that. So there's this small pocket of money.
And whether we help folks rise out of poverty
or we help stabilize SNAP, There's definitely this delicate ecosystem
that we have to navigate. I would love to talk more. What I can do is communicate. I'm in charge, I am connecting with bodegas. Next one is barber shops and just the local community. Hit me up if you want news to be spread.
Thank you very much. Mr. Harris, additional speakers for this period.
Yes, Madam President. Next is Melissa Snavely.
Thank you. Good evening. My name is Melissa Snavely
and I live at the 800 block of State Street within the city of Lancaster, and I also want to thank our veterans here tonight for their service. I want to voice my thoughts on current state and federal budget impasses that have caused potentially devastating state, county, and local crises
around funding for education, health care, food security, and heating, to name a few.
The economy, state and local, is already feeling the effects
as these budget deadlocks force cities and towns to borrow money or cut back on services and consumers to pull back on spending as businesses in turn cut back by letting workers go and safety nets are pulled defunded or used for political games real harm is being done to real people for many businesses it may mean closing shop and for many impacted community
members we're not talking about the loss of discretionary spending money we're talking about money for necessities food shelter and medicine ultimately this affects us all including the city council especially with a new administration in 2026 while focusing on long range vision for the community including and not limited to the impact of data centers water quality and pfas issues housing and city government transparency and accountability council cannot
overlook the real and urgent needs of its city residents most affected by the inability of state and federal elected officials to do their job in the past the city council has taken up and passed resolutions on difficult and controversial national and world issues, calling on U.S. senators to support the Equality Act, condemning the use of conversion therapy on minors, recognizing a woman's right to reproductive health care, and condemning the overturning of Roe v. Wade, supporting Puerto Rican self-determination, supporting the Ukrainian people in condemning
the invasion of their sovereign nation, condemning gun violence and legislative inaction, and most recently calling for a ceasefire in Gaza. of these issues were within the jurisdiction or purview of the city council however community members ask that council consider making a statement by condemning or supporting or calling for action many of the adopted resolutions i just mentioned are divisive or not universally held beliefs but i hope that we can all agree that food is a human right in the world's richest country not to mention here in agrarian lancaster county that heat in the winter or as we may soon face the need for cooling in the summer is a minimum condition for safe shelter for our most vulnerable
residents and that stability and consistency in funding and programming alleviates unnecessary
chaos and uncertainty i ask that lancaster city council consider adopting a new resolution calling on state and federal elected officials to pass budgets on time or at a minimum forfeit their pay and health insurance until a budget is passed such a resolution is unlikely to change current political stalemates but it will send a message that the city council and the city of lancaster are holding state and federal officials accountable while holding themselves accountable to the constituents as well thank you thank you very much i think your words are very resonant and i want to take a moment to to to remind folks that we don't have the option to not pass a budget
as a city in pennsylvania we're required to pass one and i think that um as we've heard from folks tonight the state budget impasse the federal government shut down the app the weaponization of the withholding of snap benefits is is wreaking havoc in our community and yet you know we are held to what seems to be sometimes a higher standard than some of those elected officials so thank you very much for your words mr. Harris do we have any additional speakers for this period we do not matter president thank you very much with that we will move to our next item on the agenda this evening which is reports requested by council confirming that we have none of those this evening mr. Harris we do not matter president thank you that will then take us to reports of committees of council these are reports from the meetings of committees that were held on November 3rd 2025 we'll begin with public safety councillor Diaz the Public Safety Committee did not meet thank you Public Works council Hirsch Thank You council president the Public Works Committee did meet we had one agenda item which is resolution 75 authorizing Department of Public Works to apply for a local shares account grant which will be heard on our agenda later this evening and that concludes report of the Public Works Committee thank you very much Economic Development Committee councillor Med Thank You council president the Economic Development Committee did not
meet in the last session Thank You Finance Committee councillor Arroyo Thank You council president the Finance Committee did meet we had three items on our agenda last week and the first was the third quarter 2000 excuse
me the third quarter report and administrative services director Tina Campbell provided the third quarterly budget report to council and compliance with the city's Home Rule Charter the major highlight of the report is that as of september 30th the city has received 73.4 of the budgeted revenue for the year and about 57.2 of the budgeted expenses we are we also heard a presentation regarding the earned income tax exemption the second report to council on the possibility of providing an exemption to low income residents in our city and then the third was the presentation of administration bill number 13 2025 which appears later on the agenda for its first reading that concludes in our my report council president thank you very much community planning committee councillor Craig thank you council president community planning did meet and we had nine items on the agenda all of which will come up on our
legislative agenda shortly perfect thank you very much and personnel committee
councillor clicks could not be here this evening councillor met I believe you have a report Thank You council president the personnel committee did meet on
November 3rd and reviewed nominations for reappointment to Lancaster downtown investment district authority which will come up in our legislative agenda and
that includes my report thank you very much that will take us to our legislative agenda and the first item on that agenda item a is nominations for appointment counselor men Thank You council president I make a motion to to reappoint the Reverend David Peck and James Wagner to the Downtown Investment District Authority
for terms from December 31st, 2025 to December 31st, 2030.
Second. Motion and a second on the nominations. Any council comments on the nominations for reappointment? Comment? Council President, if I will. Councilor Med, yes, thank you. Thank you so much.
I would just like to say that out of the two applicants, Reverend David pack I do know personally and I think he would be a great addition to be reappointed to this To this board and also James Wagner has served the board and look forward to his service until 2030
Okay. Thank you additional council comments on the reappointments comments from the public on the reappointments Hearing none. Mr. Harris. Mr. Mudd. Aye
Mr. Roya. Aye. Miss Craig. Aye. Miss Diaz
Mr. Hirsch. Aye. And President Baker. Aye. Our next items on the agenda are items for the
Heritage Conservation and Historic District. Mr. Harris if you would. There's several. Yes Madam President. Considering the following applications and recommendations from the Historical Commission
and Historical Architectural Review Board for improvements to properties within the Heritage Conservation and Historic Districts. First is L.J. Henry Holdings LLC owner of 623 East Mifflin street proposes demolition of a row of wooden garage stalls and construction of five new town
houses next is jeffrey zimmerman owner of 248 south ann street proposes demolition of a wooden garage facing new dolphin street and installation of a prefabricated shed in the rear yard and both
of those applications are recommended for approval by the historical commission and last is city of lancaster owner of 38 penn square requests alteration of entry steps installation of a
new door opening replacement of rooftop railing installation of new window shutters and installation of a security gate on a basement stairway and that application was recommended for approval
by the historical architectural review board thank you mr harris i'll hear a motion on these items Motion to approve second thank you. We have a motion and a second council Craig any additional notes for any of these items. I know we did hear two of them at our committee meeting. True. Actually there is not other than the facts that are right in front of us. Thank you very much. Any additional council comments on the proving proving the items comments from the public hearing on Mr. Harris Mr.
men aye mr. Roya aye miss Craig all right miss Diaz mr. Hirsch all right and president Baker aye that will take us to our next items on the agenda these
are ordinances there for first reading this evening again any bill gets a first read and then we'll we won't be taking any voting action on them tonight they get read into the record we begin with administration bill number 13 2025 mr. Harris in ordinance increasing the indebtedness of the city of Lancaster Lancaster County Pennsylvania by the issue of a guaranteed revenue bond in
the maximum principal amount of seven hundred and fifty six thousand one hundred and thirty two dollars for construction of new water service lines to replace lead service lines to improve the city's water conveyance system
fixing the form dates interest and maturity thereof making a covenant for payment of the debt service on the bond providing for the filing of the required documentation with the Department of Community and Economic Development to incur and exclude additional debt of the government governmental unit providing
for the appointment of a second sinking fund depository for the bond providing
for the authorized signatories and authorizing execution sale and delivery thereof thank you very much mr harris so again this is a first read this evening this has came up this came up through finance committee council royal anything to add thank you council president
uh just wanted to add that the total cost of the line replacement is going to be 1.7 million
953 000 of that will be a grant um and the remaining which is being funded uh through this loan uh 756 thousand dollars uh will be at a one percent fixed rate for 30 years Thank you very much. Important to note that very low rate. Counselors any comments for the first reading of this bill 13 from the public. Good evening. Darlene Byrd 200 block of South End Street. I just wonder is there any way we can get a report. We borrowed a lot of money bonds and stuff for the lead paint pipe replacement. Do we know what pipes have been replaced
and what yet needs to be replaced. I mean we keep borrowing money and I haven't seen. i see them working on the roads but i don't know if that's part of this lead paint uh lead um pipes that they're changing is there a report of what has been done in the city what yet needs to be
done in the city where this money that we're getting ready to borrow is going to be used at in the city sure thank you miss uh miss bird what i have in front of me is what we covered at our meeting um and i'm sure that there is a report that we could request from public works on locations that are remaining but this one as in for a note would cover 108 new lines um that's what we know right now thank you any additional comments from the public on the first reading of the bill hearing none we'll close this one and we'll move to our next item on the agenda pull up the right i had my committee meeting notes up uh so for first reading administration bill number 14 2025 mr harris if he would please yes madam president in ordinance of the lancaster city
council amending chapter 300 of the code of the city of lancaster to reasoning rezone a portion
of the property identified as lancaster county talk tax parcel id number three three nine two 0 3 2 0 0 0 0 0 0 from the c3 district regional commercial to the CM district
central manufacturing and to permit self storage facilities without size restriction in the CM district central manufacturing on lots containing a minimum of three acres and a maximum of five acres which do not have direct access to a public street and are in existence as of july 1st 2025 subject to additional requirement providing for the repeal of inconsistent ordinances providing for the severability
ordinance and providing that the ordinance shall take effect 20 days from the date of its adoption
thank you very much mr harris we did have a presentation on this at our committee meeting
Councillor Craig anything additional to add for the first reading this bill would amend the zoning ordinance to allow for self storage facilities of more than 20,000 square feet by right in the central manufacturing district and zoning map amendment to rezone a 2.55 acre tract from regional commercial to central manufacturing
Thank you very much. I'll also note that While there's also a second reading of this bill required at that time
There will be a hearing as required for any zoning amendments. So that should be scheduled for our meeting on the 25th And we'll have a we will re Present the information that was presented to us on the third at that time counselors any additional comments on the first read councilor I'm Ed Thank You council president my only question was I know the County Planning Commission was going to review this amendment for consistency I just wanted to know if we have that report back from the Planning Commission that's a good question I think they have 45 days and I'm not sure ah great how fortuitous feel free to move that microphone wherever you need it to be if you could just start with your name and who you're representing
for that question thank you very much my name is peter wurtz i'm an attorney with mcneese wallace and eric here on behalf of the initial petitioner 1031 dillardville road lp i can respond to the question concerning the county's review we did receive a staff recommendation of approval from the county planning commission the planning commission met yesterday afternoon at 3 p.m they did adopt the staff recommendation of approval thank you for that update appreciate it
any additional council comments on the first reading of the bill comments from the public on the first reading I think about the storage a self storage facility and I know how that could help the neighborhood we're talking about alley 59 that has all self storages and could be used differently my concern would be we have a lot of rental properties that even though it's against the law they rent out their garages and the house separately most of them use it for cars or not so much storage stuff but a lot of cars and motorcycles and i wonder if this large facility is going to accommodate the residents the little small storages that we have within the city and would they be affordable thank you ms bird i don't know that we have those answers but i will also say that this impacts facilities over 20 000 square feet so any additional comments from the public on the first reading of the bill good evening good evening susie gomez 800 block east
orange um i just want a second uh darlene bird's attempt to get an answer for that thank you
thank you i don't think we have that to repeat i don't think we have the information from the proposed tenant of that particular space that would be up to them Any additional comments in the public on the bill on bill 14? Good evening. Good evening My name is Carlo Gonzalez from 300 block or so any street and also member of a southern consent enable The same we come back again to try to find some answer about what we request in the last couple week meeting What going on with Ali? 59 and what going on with mr. Tom
Snyder, what is the real goal he pretend to do in our neighborhood, because according to what we see, he pretend to bring his business of heavy truck, whole truck, more than 17,000 pounds, class four, class five, running behind our houses, where we have a lot of children playing around, a lot of kids from the school going through the alleyway to going to McCaskey or Mill
School, Washington School and there are a lot of older people also walk on the back not to walk to the front from any street so most of the children use the alleyway
we don't want to get big truck passing through there
all the time so that is
our major concern I'm not sure
when this person present the proposal
to perform some work in there what kind of thing have been hiding under his permit because according to the requesting that we have nobody know
anything or what he was final intention so that's what really we need to get answered for that we keep follow up about this thing situation thank you very much about safety but this is the safety situation for kid thank you very much I'll just address I know that that's a separate concern than what's being discussed in the bill however this bill does address and restrict storage from residential
areas so it is tangential to that part of your concern so thank you any additional comments on bill 14 for our first read this evening hearing now we'll close that and we will move on to oh
there's one more for first read uh bill number 15 2025 mr harris if you would please yes madam
president an ordinance of the lancaster city council increasing the annual compensation of the members of city council from eight thousand dollars per annum to ten thousand per annum
providing for the repeal of inconsistent ordinances providing for the severability ordinance and providing that the ordinance shall take effect in accordance with the charter of the city of lancaster thank you very much mr harris uh councillor craig um you did talk us through this this was your bill anything additional to add for this meeting um just to reiterate the things that we talked about in the first meeting and at committee meeting that it's been short one year of two decades since council has had a salary increase and you know the duties
of council have changed according to the charter the duties have been increased as well as um you
know the boards commissions things that council members are required to be on along with performing their council duties um this would not affect anyone other than i believe counselor ahmed because it would not take effect until um january of 2028 thank you and only because he's been recently re-elected true and i think it will affect his last two years but um in any event i remember him saying at committee meeting that he would not be voting he would abstain correct um thank you counselor craig um and i'd also make a mention in this that the home rule charter decreased the overall compensation package for members of council by removing the health care that would have been required that would have greatly outpaced this increase that where there hasn't been one for 20 years so i do think that that's important to also restate at this first reading so thank you councillors any any additional comments for the first reading of bill 15. comments from the public on the first read of the bill hearing none we'll close the first reading thank you very much that will take us to our resolutions tonight on our legislative agenda we begin with administration resolution number 69 2025 mr harris if you would a resolution of
of the Council of the City of Lancaster authorizing the filing of the
Commonwealth Finance and Authority local share account application for funding in
the amount not to exceed 1 million dollars for Union Community Cares Lancaster Southeast Health Center motion to approve second we have a motion and a
second this is the first of a number of local shares applications that have come before us councillor Craig if you have anything to add for this one or in general this one was for Union care mr. Reichenbach Reichenbach presented to us chief impact officer of Union Community Care said his organization is seeking a million dollars of local shares to help fund renovations to its 625 South Duke Street facility work has been done in recent years to the dental and the pharmacy areas but the medical facilities have not been renovated in decades they see and they see more than 10,000 patients annually at this site
thank you very much counselor Craig members of council and for the public
I'll just remind we've done a number of these before but local shares account program is administered by the state of Pennsylvania involves gaming funds and distributed across the state and they require a municipality to um to sign off on the application but ultimately none of the funds come from from our city budget and nor are we indebted or have any obligation for for any of them so um any additional council comments on resolution 69
for union community care from the public hearing none mr harris mr med aye mr arroyo aye miss craig
aye miss diaz aye mr hirsch aye president peke aye that will move us to resolution number 70 2025
mr harris when you're ready a resolution of the council of the city of lancaster
authorizing the filing of the common commonwealth finance authority local share account application
for funding in the amount not to exceed one million dollars for southwest end holdings sleigh maker community renewal project motion to approve second a motion and a second
counselor craig anything additional for this one um just the notes that um we went over at committee um union vision care miss domingo union vision care child care founder is seeking a million dollars in local share grants to help with renovations at 117 southwest end avenue the former sleigh maker lock factory home home to 35 small businesses funds will help pay for energy efficient upgrades storm water management improvements green infrastructure parking lot repaving etc etc thank you very much counselors any additional comments on resolution 70 from the public good evening vicki wright smith 100 block south marshall street so this is the second one
for a million dollars i'm i'm astonished at how much these uh how much these local shares are so is this automatic so once they apply they automatically get it no okay nope we we um just not to eat into your time if you have additional but the local shares requires that a municipality
assist with the application but it is not a guarantee and they can apply for up to a million dollars but they're not guaranteed if they get approved to get all of that dollars all of those dollars they might get a certain amount but not that much okay but these last two asked for a
million right that's the maximum and many most organizations apply for the max a lot of money
in the gaming i guess huh yep must be night state nice state government would be nice if they'd open
back up pass a budget okay any additional comments for resolution number 70. good evening good evening um i just wanted to make sure that there's a fair share to all business owners like we keep seeing the same people getting funded or businesses getting funded. Is it something that's open to like are you sharing information with the city of Lancaster's so that they know
that these local share funds are available. Like you use advertising. So these are advertised to the P.A. Department of Community and Economic Development
and we don't have any say on who gets approved
and who does not. But anyone is welcome to apply. ELLIE WILSON- Anyone is welcome to apply. That's what I wanted to make sure. There's certain eligibility and there's a long list of things but yeah. Is there anyone like teaching that or sharing that with the public. From the Pennsylvania Department of Community and Economic Development.
And also the city of Lancaster. We hold an annual workshop related to local
surrogates account and other funding opportunities to make sure that everyone has awareness of those and that happens in the fall. Second right at the spring the spring. Thank you. They can anticipate this timeline. Thank you. Thank you Any additional comments on resolution 70 hearing now, mr. Harris, mr. Mudd. Ah Mr. Roy. Oh, aye
Miss Craig. All right. Miss Diaz. Mr. Hirsch. All right president Baker. Hi
Similarly our next item is resolution number 71
one twenty twenty five mr. Harris a resolution of the council of the city of Lancaster authorizing the filing of the Commonwealth Finance Authority local
share account application for funding in the amount not to exceed 1 million dollars for the Thaddeus Stevens foundations Thaddeus Stevens College of Technology Stevens home building program second we have a motion and a second Councillor Craig anything to add. Thaddeus Stevens Foundation. Miss Smith and her associate Miss Gurman executive director of Thaddeus Stevens presented seeking one million dollars in local shares to help fund a construction construction of the duplex four of this of the student home construction program. the duplex is part of a larger project that will construct eight units on on that particular site these homes are sold with deeds restrictions requiring that they be owner-occupied thank you very much counselor Craig counselors any additional comments on resolution 71 from the public hearing none mr. Harris Mr. Mann aye Mr. Arroyo aye Ms. Craig aye Ms. Diaz Mr. Hirsch aye and President Becker aye that will bring us to resolution 72 2025 Mr. Harris if you
would a resolution of the Council of the City of Lancaster authorizing the filing of the Commonwealth Finance Authority local share account
application for funding in the amount not to exceed 1 million dollars for South and Concerned Neighbors Stevens project second we have a motion and a second council Craig South Ann Street Concerned Neighbors miss Burt presented to us of Southeast Concerned Neighbors and is seeking 1 million dollars in local shares funds to help fund construction of a two-story building on land donated by the Thaddeus Stevens Foundation at 615 Stevens Avenue the total cost of the project is 3.5 million and southeast concern neighbors has been awarded about half of that to date thank you very much councillors any additional comments on resolution 72 from the public yes ma'am this is blowing my mind a little bit so southeast south and concerned neighbors already have half of the money that they need you said so you could just keep coming back and asking for a million dollars each time no they their funds were awarded from a different area other than the local shares okay so do we know how much they've already gotten from the
local shares yeah for this project for this project this project okay thank you
any additional comments from the public on resolutions 72 hearing none mr.
Harris mr. man I mr. Roya I miss Craig all right miss Diaz all right mr. Hirsch
all right the president pick a I switching gears a little bit we'll cut
back to these resolution number 73 2025 mr. Harris a resolution of the council the city of Lancaster approving a flag raising on February 24th 2026 to acknowledge Dominican Independence Day brought forth by the Dominican Association of Lancaster motion to approve second thank you we have a motion and a second counselors we discussed this at our committee meeting
on the third the Dominican Association of Lancaster submitted a timely application to hold a flag raising on February 24th 2026 to mark Dominican
Independence Day we have this before us to approve any additional comments from Council on the resolution from the public hearing none mr. Harris mr. min
aye mr. Roy oh hi miss Greg all right miss Diaz mr. Hirsch all right
president Baker hi coming back to local shares administration resolution 74 2025
mr. Harris a resolution the council the city of Lancaster authorizing the filing
of the Commonwealth Finance Authority local share account application for funding in the amount not to exceed 1 million dollars for chestnut housing
corporations Dinah Hill apartments motion to approve second we have a motion and a second council Craig thanks council president I just found some more things on local shares to try and help everybody understand just a little bit better the city's grant manager described the local shares account program to us in committee she said local share funds are our state gaming revenue which is reinvested into Pennsylvania communities grants may range from twenty five thousand to a million dollars no local match is required the city must apply on behalf of local nonprofit organizations for those organizations to receive funding since 2022 when the city was first eligible to apply for local shares account grants the city has made 30 applications of of those applications 11 have
have been funded for the total of 5.9 million dollars applications for 2024 remain pending
this year the city expects to submit 10 additional application of applications each of those applications require a resolution approved by City Council thank you very much councillor Craig okay and now resolution 74 chestnut Street housing mr. Martin executive director of chestnut Street housing is seeking a million dollars in local shares this would fund renovations of the former strawberry hill restaurant into 11 affordable apartments and two community office spaces total cost for the project is expected to be 3.8 million of that 2.4 million has been committed to the project to date thank you very much counselor craig an important context on the program itself and just anecdotally i think for members of council we've seen an increase in number of applications that have come in for this program so people are taking advantage of it uh counselors any additional comments on resolution number 74 from the public hearing none
mr harris mr med aye mr arroyo aye miss greg aye miss diaz aye mr hirsch all right and president begay aye and that will take us to resolution number 75 2025. mr harris if you would please a resolution of the council of the city of lancaster authorizing the filing of the commonwealth
finance authority local share account application for funding in the amount not to exceed one
million dollars for state street for street safety and storm water management improvements for the city of lancaster's east ross street green infrastructure project motion to approve second
we have a motion and a second council craig this is um this is 75 right did i say 74 i apologize um confirming that i have the right thing in front of me sorry 75 75 public works thank you yes I believe this one's for me I'm sorry about that that's okay this one came up through Public Works I was just I was on a roll all good all good so yes resolution 75 authorizes the city to apply for local shares account municipal governments can also apply for these funds you may recall that the Public Works Department applied for LSA funds for the improvements that are happening at some parks in the city at the Joe Jackson tot lot in South End Park.
This this grant is for up to a million dollars for green
infrastructure improvements on East Ross Street. The green infrastructure improvements would cover capture stormwater and help with localized flooding in the north stormwater basement basin of the city
running on East Ross Street from North Queen to North Ship and Street projected total
costs of the project including the designs about 1.5 to 1.6 million dollars though without the lsa grant it may not be financially feasible the projected timeline would be designed in 2026 with construction occurring in 2027 and hopefully completed by 2028 with the hopes of having that completed prior to scheduled street paving in 2029 and 2030. these capital costs are all and timeline are accounted for in the city's capital budget which we adopted earlier this year thank you very much counselor hirsch and i appreciate the city looking for these grant opportunities whenever we're able for these very expensive infrastructure projects any additional council comments on resolution 75 from the public good evening good evening i just wanted to add
that it would be appreciated if we see other nonprofit organizations getting these types of fundings not just the same ones over and over again because a
lot of these here mentioned they've already gotten funding and I understand it's from local shares I totally get it but it's amazing to me to see the same ones over and over again get funded thank you very much I'm gonna say please please send folks to those info sessions in the spring and encourage them to
apply there's certainly to your point a lot of money on the table additional
council comments on resolution number 75 hearing on mr. Harris mr. Mudd aye mr. Royo aye miss Craig all right miss Diaz mr. Hirsch all right the president
Baker hi that will take us to resolution number 76 2025 mr. Harris a resolution the city council of the city of lancaster authorizing the proper officials of the city of lancaster to enter into an agreement with the central market trust and directing the appropriate
city officials to make any and all actions to consummate the transactions contemplated by the agreement motion to approve second we have a motion and a second counselors we took this up at our committee of the whole I'll just quickly note that this updates the original agreement
with the central market trust which was made in 2006 and later amended in 2015.
the update was done at the request of the central market trust in in order to try to actually match what is what our current practices and define terms in in clearer ways a lot has changed with the with the central market trust over the last several years and so I think that this is long overdue and also director Stephen Campbell reviewed with us some highlights of the agreement which includes having a capital plan which will be reviewed annually and aligned with the condition report on the structure and systems of the building and this is coming up also through through Public Works councilors do you have anything additional to add on the agreement nothing to add thank you very much councillors any additional comments on the resolution comments from the public on the road on resolution 76 hearing none mr. Harris mr. Mudd aye mr. Arroyo aye miss Craig miss Diaz mr. Hirsch all right the president Baker aye last but not least we have administration resolution 77 2025 mr.
Harris if you would please a resolution of the council the city of lancaster authorizing the sale of 843 fremont street through the use of a licensed real estate broker and establishing the criteria to be utilized in reviewing offers to acquire said property and directing the proper officials of the city of lancaster to take any and all actions necessary to comply with this resolution and complete the sale of the property necessitated here thereby motion to approve second I have a motion and a second council Craig
Thank You council president as in committee director Delph presented this and reminded us that earlier this year council approved an amendment to the city code to allow sale of city owned real estate with a licensed broker this This resolution authorizes the city to contract with Compass Real Estate Group to market 843 Fremont Street, having previously contracted with and understanding how the city functions and what the goal is. The resolution clarifies the realtor's role in the marketing plan. Thank you very much, Councilor Craig. Councilors, any additional comments on the resolution? From the public. Good evening. 200 Block of South Hand Street. I remember when council passed a resolution, there was a lot of pushback from the community about being able to sell city-owned property to a realtor.
It was well explained through council that this was just giving them another option
so that now they would have three different ways of getting rid of city property. At that time, I think the mayor said there was nobody that was interested. there was no way of getting rid of the fire station since that announcement was made i know
there are were at least two and maybe more organizations that approach approached many of the council members and the mayor of having an interest in getting this property understanding
that if we do sell it to a realtor there's a cost factor and i'm wondering what that cost factor might be in him marketing and putting this out there that the two nonprofit organizations that I know of that approach the city about wanting that property. Do we have any idea what that factor is. I appreciate that.
So just to clarify this resolution doesn't
sell it to a realtor it allows the realtor to market the property.
When we before we had this option there was a public
a request for proposal or mayor was a request for proposal
or a bid a bid process thank you which yielded no results.
The ability to have a realtor market it means that we can open it up more widely to in addition to including but not limited to any organizations that would be interested. We did hear about any fees at our committee meeting. Director Delfz I apologize I forget what the fee was in the agreement I'm looking for it here. But I do know we don't receive anything until the sale is complete and it is contingent upon the actual sales price. So it is a proportional amount.
DIRECTOR MACKAY And I'll just add to that while you're getting seated that it is ultimately council's decision whether or not to factor in the potential proposed sale price. And so if council were to determine that a use for a community benefit organization that would not pay property taxes is the desire of council, then that is weighted in the determination on that matrix that was provided to council as part of this.
So this is not necessarily to sell it to the highest bidding or the highest proposed purchase price, but it does allow for a variety of options to be presented to council for their consideration. Thank you. Director Delfz? Yes. Good evening, City Council. In answer to your question, President Baquet, it was a little bit difficult to find, but there is specific information in the draft contract that states the broker's fee will be the higher of 6% of the purchase price or $29,700.
Also, just wanted to add briefly, I appreciate that the mayor had reminded us about the evaluation criteria for ultimately selecting a buyer. I just wanted to note those, again, for city council and for the public.
The criteria listed here are compatibility with the comprehensive plan, value add to the comprehensive plan, compatibility with the neighborhood, value add to the neighborhood, offer price, and terms of the offer. The offer price weight is only 20% of the total criteria. Great. I appreciate revisiting that. Thank you. Sure. any additional comments from the public on resolution 77 hello I just wanted to share that it yielded no results because the interest was overlooked this
specific resolution was spoken about by the public and they brought concerns in regards to communities needing it for specific reasons as to why we're going
through so much like homelessness shelter it's an enormous amount of issues that we are dealing
with in a community that or that two specific organizations brought to the light and stated that it could be used for usage for the community for the people for the taxpayers it could there was presentations presented and it was overlooked okay i just feel that in all reality what is
compass's goal do you know miss craig can you share an email with me so you can at least let me know compass real estate's goal since you mentioned that well i'll give you my email later but i just want to know what you know what is their goal okay thank you and if i could just clarify um uh council president we did receive one um response to the bid and it was um for a museum i'll describe it as a museum um and the two proposals that i believe that council may be aware of and that have been brought to the attention of director delfs and i came in after that bid had been closed and that we had been discussing openly at council how to dispense of this particular property. And so they are more than welcome to submit a proposal for council consideration. Thank you. Yes, ma'am. Good evening again. Vicki Wright-Smith, 100 Block of South Marshall Street. So my question is, a lot of times when you enter into real estate agreements with Realtors there's a time limit one year this agreement terminates and we can reevaluate thank you any additional comments from the public on resolution 77 hearing none mr. Harris mr. min aye mr. Arroyo aye miss Craig aye miss Diaz nay mr. Hirsch aye the president Baker aye Thank You councillors that is the conclusion of our legislative agenda this evening that will bring us to our second public comment period again open for comments on comments on issues not on the agenda duration of comments again is limited to three minutes per speaker and please begin with your name and block of residence for a meeting record if anyone wishes to speak during the second public comment period please come forward at this time you can go right on a pad we'll just line everybody up thank you good evening I just want to comment on what Carlos was talking about about alleyway 59 and what's going on there I do want to want you to know that we have been working with director Steve Campbell and trying to get information and find out what's going on i think we're feeling it's not happening fast enough but we are in communications but we do really want to know what's going on there right now we have a gentleman who had bought some land back there and is planning on bringing big trucks i guess we really haven't found out what the plan is we have reached out to him as a
a non-profit organization in a neighborhood community he refuses to speak with us so it's not like you know we can even try to work something out because there's no communication there but we are asking the city council and uh the city to find out and let us know what is going
on there what's allowed to be there what they're not allowed to do there because we see stuff going on it has been quiet for a little while but a lot of the residents were getting um tickets where they used to park there for 47 years behind that alleyway you know we have this uh residential
permanent parking trial coming up this is all going to affect that area when you're telling
residents who used to park in their alleyway they can no longer park there and their blocks not getting residential permanent parking and the other blocks around them are we know what that does everybody's going to go to their block the park so it's very important that we find out what's going on what can be done how we can as a neighborhood organize play a role in what's happening back there you know whether it's getting to sit down and talk to the guy that bought the
property and what his intentions are at one point we heard he's going to build an office he's going to be about bringing in junk trucks it's a junk business and he's going to have these big trucks
we are really concerned about safety we have the schools down there the children use that alleyway to walk down to washington and the hand all the time so it is a very it's a safety concern too so if we can get some information sooner than later we would appreciate it thank you very much ms byrd additional comments for this period good evening good evening my name is austin mountain uh 400 block of north prince street uh past few weeks i've been going back and forth with the city of lancaster because i'm trying to throw a christmas party for the city uh where we give away over a thousand boxes of food from blessings of hope they're about 30 40 pounds of food we're trying to give away a bunch of diapers wipes formula as much stuff as we can provide and like my first response i got was that it takes 180 days to get that permit and you could try for next christmas so especially if i wasn't so stubborn i probably would have just shrugged my shoulders and kept going but i'm pretty stubborn so i've been going back and forth and right now we're at the point where i'm recommended to go get a private lot to do it so i'm kind of asking if anybody has a private lot that's large enough to accommodate it and i'm also trying to find out what the actual need is because our plan is do at least a thousand boxes which would be about 40 000 pounds of food but if i can make sure i have the demand to fill i'd like to do more and then the same thing with the diapers wipes formula blankets we just want to throw a party and give away a bunch of stuff to the community and i'm having a hard time getting the ability to do that so council president if i may yes and then i have a question for you so we might have the same partner with blessings of hope in the past and i would be more than happy to assist you in helping to disseminate much needed supplies and food to our community we've done that in a lot of different ways and if you're open to partnership with the city of lancaster we're open to helping to facilitate this as a joint event that would help you leap through those permitting requirements yeah that's all i want to do i just want to give this stuff away thank you happy to help please give me your contact information thank you thank you for
sharing and also just as a question where was the original intent to have this so my goal was to
shut down the section of north prince street in front of the cargas and just i wanted to bring food trucks that's why yeah the whole thing and then we tried penn square and they got shut down
so i'm i'm just trying to find a place yeah having the street shut down gets complicated but i think
we can i think we can find a good solution that's going to benefit as long as you're open to some other options then street closures and we have a lot of other events that are happening so there's probably just some conflict we can come up with a plan yeah i'm fine for this year But I want to do it this year then so we can do it bigger next year and just keep compounding on itself. Okay Thank you. Thank you very much Any additional comments for this component period good evening again, sir Carlo Gonzales from 300 block of Sawan Street Just to insist again concerning about alleyway 59 How the city can rule in favor on only one person who is not resident or our neighbor and in this in the proportion of our 40 family more than 40 family and children hundred children that I will be affected for the unsafety business that he have around there with their heavy vehicle and all
the consideration so that's what I try to understand how the city can protect
one person in this regard of 40 more family in our block he don't live here he's not part of that one our residents people he just came to make money in favor of what of himself one person against all the neighbors thank you very much any additional comments for this period yeah i just um susie gomez 800 block of east orange i just wanted to say real quickly um partnering with our neighborhood leaders would be best to um i feel to release anything uh as far as you know what's what the um approach is to help the uh communities um this is the reason why the biden administration has awarded nearly 15 billion dollars in homelessness assistance funding through various programs, including $1.5 billion specifically for homeless shelters and related
services. The funding aims to provide critical resources to help people experiencing homelessness and support local communities in their efforts to address the issue. When the Trump administration came in, he asked for receipts. He wanted to see where this $15 billion was going to
and who utilized it so we saw the outcome this is for the people that are listening
for the public for the taxpayers and for people that are really interested in what's going on so these states municipalities you guys were all awarded funding to take care of the homelessness crisis in the biden administration which you can't produce anything of and we are still here
with homelessness crisis and the money is gone church wall services furloughed all their
employees because they got the money and a lot of organizations throughout the city state and the United States are dealing with the same issue so how can we trust an administration to utilize funding properly for specific needs in a
crisis or in our community if you guys are stealing it thank you any additional comments for this period see none I will close the public comment period for the meeting and thank everyone we will now move to the next item on our agenda the
report of the mayor mayor sir Achi thank you very much council president tonight I'm providing a brief update on the community benefits agreement and the
timeline related to the data centers negotiations between the sitter of Lancaster City of Lancaster Carissa Technology Parks and their partners are
ongoing and we are nearing completion while I hesitate to give a firm date
since we've missed the last two I'm encouraged by the significant progress over the past two weeks and also the need to move forward before the holiday season I've asked the council president to call a special meeting dedicated solely to reviewing deliberating on and voting on the community benefits agreement she has agreed Thank You council president and the meeting is scheduled for next Thursday November 20th at 6 p.m. again that's Thursday november 20th at 6 p.m here in council chambers i want to briefly talk about the actual agreement
as you may recall negotiations have proceed proceeded on two major fronts the first is
the environmental and quality of life commitments and the second pertain to community investments in addition to the environmental commitments that i shared with council previously and that
can be found on the city's website carissa technology parks and their affiliates have
committed to powering the regular operations of the buildings on the two
proposed AI hub campuses with clean energy due to timing of the power purchase agreements which naturally will occur at a later time after the buildings are constructed the community benefits agreement includes performance incentives and accountability provisions to help ensure the city and Carissa that technology parks reach their sustainability goals as it pertains to community investments carissa will contribute a definitive dollar amount under the terms of the draft cba to two funds
the first an economic development fund is to promote the economic vitality of lancaster city
and foster the economic mobility and success of residents of lancaster city uses of this fund
include projects and programs that enhance local business development and technical assistance as well as workforce development the lancaster economic development company will play a formal role in developing a strategy and administering the deployment of monies from the economic development fund which will be managed by the lancaster county community foundation the second fund the sustainable development and clean energy fund will be managed by the city of lancaster its purpose is to advance environmental sustainability in the city of lancaster and will draw guidance from the city's climate action plan comprehensive plan and other related initiatives taken together we have negotiated the framework for the community benefit agreement to address environmental impacts and to make voluntary contributions to the benefit of our community this is progress and we have some final language that we are still negotiating however i want to thank carissa and its affiliated partners for their responsiveness to the concerns that have been brought forward i also want to thank council for your forbearance as these negotiations have
proceeded finally carissa technology parks is hosting an open house tomorrow night november
12th at the ware center 42 north prince street from five to seven i encourage residents to attend
the open house to learn more about the project and to engage with the carissa team i'm pleased that they're hosting this event to talk with the community directly so please spread the word thank
you very much thank you very much mayor sirachi i'm very much looking forward to getting that agreement in front of council members of council you did receive communication from me earlier this evening announcing that meeting it is already on the city website and it will be properly advertised as well. That will bring us to council press report of president of council.
The only thing I want to bring to your everyone's attention
is that it is the winter weather season is closing in upon us and while we hope it is light it seems like a great time to mention red rose alerts. There is some material about red rose alerts sitting on the table over there if you'd like to take it looks like this it's in English and in Spanish you can scan to get the information so you don't have to take another piece of paper with you but if you're not signed up already red rose alerts allows you to receive notes on closures weather related
emergencies service cancellations severe weather unexpected road closures etc and you'll get those alerts how you want to receive them so if you'd like a call if you'd like a text message if you'd
like an email if you'd like all of the above you get to decide how you want to get that information please share that with your family and friends as we uh as the weather gets colder it would be good to have in place. That concludes my report this evening. Next item is council comments.
Councilors any comments this evening.
Councillor Hirsch.
Thank you council president. I just want to address some of the concerns that I heard about you know what's going on with SNAP
and with the federal and state budgets.
I feel you know the anxiety that that people are feeling
on that like I witness it working in government finance by day and you know kind of through this by night as well.
And I don't feel like I have good answers to that. The economic the national economic winds blow the direction that they do. And there's a lot of that that really we don't
get to choose whether that happens to us. We only choose how we respond to it.
and so I just want to encourage folks to continue to plug into not just you know I want to shout out organizations that are doing really critical work to you
know feed folks in the community community meals are being served as I understand it 24 7 365 but also you know many of our social service providers there's too many to name but I did want to shout out a neighbor that has been doing really incredible work Rick canard with his lockers for the homeless initiative last Saturday a couple folks were working on building those and he has announced on the Facebook page if you want to follow for updates you can
follow lockers for the homeless Lancaster on Facebook that they're going be working again this Sunday uh November 16th from nine to three um it's at his uh place at 224 North Shippen Street um just want to encourage to maybe consider going out uh encourage folks to
go out and consider helping build those uh lockers so that um folks that are sleeping outside have a
place to store items um and I think it's just going to be initiatives like that um and the
other one I would say that's really important is just talking to your neighbors hearing from them hearing what's going on in their day to day lives. I think both of those things are really important but I did just want to shout out that particular opportunity for folks to help build the infrastructure that's going to serve our neighbors here in our community. So sorry if that was a little long winded but I just wanted to put that out there. Thank you very much Councillor Hirsch.
any additional council comments this evening yes if I may I just want to do a shout out to our union rep that's here it's nice seeing you mr. trout thank you
Thank You councillor Diaz any additional council comments councillor med Thank You council president I just wanted to make one note that the home rural transition committee did meet for our last meeting on Wednesday October 29th and we are on pace to have the Administrative Code and the Ethics Commission by the deadline I just want to thank Mayor Sirachi Commissioner John McGran and the city solicitor who I was able to share that committee with and it looks like we got it done on time so just wanted to report that we did meet and those meetings have now been ended thank you very much and thank you for serving and everyone who who worked through that to get that done before the end of the year and we look forward to having the full admin code before council soon right any additional council comments making sure all right
having reached the end of our agenda we'll hear a motion for adjournment motion to adjourn second I have a motion and a second all in favor aye we're adjourned thank you